bitterstrawberry.org 2019-01-31

# Privacy Policy | BitterStrawberry

The protection of your personal data and your privacy is very important to us. This Privacy Policy applies to personal information that we process from you in order to provide you with our products and services at [www.bitterstrawberry.com](https://www.bitterstrawberry.com/).

Here you will find information about who we are and how you can contact us. We also explain how and why we process personal information about you, to whom we transmit it and how long we store it. Finally, we will inform you about the rights that you have regarding the processing of your personal data by us.

## 1\. Who we are and how you can contact us

We, BITTERSTRAWBERRY HOLDING AG, Gaiserstrasse 129, 9050 Appenzell, Switzerland, represented by its President of the Board Gian Carlo Scalisi (hereinafter "BITTERSTRAWBERRY") are responsible for the processing of your personal data in connection with the use of our products and services under [www.bitterstrawberry.com](https://www.bitterstrawberry.com/). Our local representative in the European Union is MOBLAB SRL, 2nd District, Frunzei Street, no 26 , 3rd floor, 021534 Bucharest, Romania.

We have appointed a Data Protection Officer, whom you can reach at [privacy@bitterstrawberry.com](mailto:privacy@bitterstrawberry.com) or by mail at MOBLAB SRL, Frunzei Street, no 26, 3rd floor, 021534 Bucharest, 2nd District, Romania.

## 2\. How and why we process your personal information

In the following we inform you about which of your personal data we process, when you use our products and services at www.bitterstrawberry.com. We also explain for what purpose we use this data and on what legal basis we do so.

## 2.1 Data that we process on the basis of a consent, Art. 6 para. 1a) DS-GVO

### 2.1.1 Newsletter Subscription

If you subscribe to our newsletter, we use and store the e-mail address provided for this purpose to send you our newsletter regularly.

It goes without saying that your subscription to the Newsletter is voluntary and you may revoke your consent to the receipt of the newsletter at any time with future effect by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link contained in each of our newsletters. The lawfulness of the processing on the basis of your consent until the revocation remains unaffected.

We also use the messaging service Mailchimp ([https://mailchimp.com](https://mailchimp.com/)), by The Rocket Science Group LLC d/b/a MailChimp, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 USA (<https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy>). You can always unsubscribe / op-out on each e-mail you received after opting in.

### 2.1.2 Use of messaging services

You can subscribe to news about topics that interest you through various messaging services. For this you need a messaging account of the respective provider. For the use of a messaging service, depending on the messenger, data is transmitted to us. The respective data protection regulations of the messaging service provider apply:

| Messaging - Service & Provider | Privacy Policy of the provider | Data submitted to BITTERSTRAWBERRY  
---|---|---|---  
| Whatsapp, Whats App Inc., 650 Castro Street, Suite 120-219 Mountain View, CA 94041, USA | [www.whatsapp.com/legal/#Privacy](https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/#Privacy) | Telephone number, user name (if necessary first and last name), device of use and all messages sent to the service  
| Facebook Messenger, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA | [www.facebook.com/about/privacy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy) | Facebook ID, first and last name, profile picture, location, time zone, gender, and all messages sent to the service  
  
Websites linked to messages may retrace that you have accessed the website through the respective messaging service. Messages sent to BITTERSTRAWBERRY are read and edited by a dedicated team and are therefore not confidential. The use of a messaging service is, of course, voluntary. If you subscribe to a messaging service and no longer wish to use it, you can unsubscribe from the future service at any time by sending a „Stop“ message or by deleting the contact from the phonebook. The lawfulness of the processing on the basis of your consent until the revocation remains unaffected.

We also use Firebase from Google Inc. 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ([https://firebase.google.com](https://firebase.google.com/)). Firebase sends push notifications over browsers and phones and tracks the user when clicking on the link. On each notification you can unsubscribe them on each notification over your phone or browser where you receive the message if you opted-in before.

### 2.1.3 Use of fan pages in social networks

If you use social networks, the purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by the social networks as well as your rights in this regard and setting options for the protection of your privacy are always based on the privacy policy of the respective social network.

| Messaging - Service & Provider | Privacy Policy of the provider  
---|---|---  
| Facebook, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA |  <https://www.facebook.com/help/203587239679209>  
<http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php>  
| Google+, Google Inc., Google Inc. 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA |  [www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy](https://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy)  
| Twitter, Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA |  [twitter.com/privacy](http://twitter.com/privacy)  
| Instagram, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA |  [help.instagram.com/155833707900388/](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388)  
  
When you visit our Fan Pages on social networks and comment on and / or rate posts, or send us personal messages through these networks, we process the personal information provided in that context as your name to respond to your comments and messages. Of course, you can also visit our fan pages without providing us with personal data.

## 2.2. Data that we process for the performance of a contract, Art. 6 (1b) DS-GVO

### 2.2.1 Contact

If you contact us (for example by email), we will process and store your personal information such as name, e-mail address and, if applicable, customer number in order to process your request.

Providing contact and (if you are a BITTERSTRAWBERRY customer) contract information such as your customer number is required to answer your request. Otherwise we cannot not process your request or not satisfactorily.

### 2.2.2 Contract with BITTERSTRAWBERRY / Login as a customer

If you conclude a contract with BITTERSTRAWBERRY via our website [www.bitterstrawberry.com](https://www.bitterstrawberry.com/), we process and store the contractual data specified in this framework (e.g. purchased object/subscription, name, postal address, e-mail address, payment method) for the purpose of contract execution. As a customer, you can also log into the customer area of the website using your email address and your password.

The provision of the above mentioned personal information is required to comply with the subscription agreement concluded with you. If you do not provide us with this information, we may not be able to complete the subscription agreement or perform it properly.

We also use phone verification for account verifications on our platform using technology from Nexmo Inc., 217 Second Street, 4th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, ([https://www.nexmo.com](https://www.nexmo.com/)), (<https://www.nexmo.com/privacy-policy>). Opt-out instructions are sent with the respective messages.

### 2.2.3 Payment details and Bank / Creditcard Data

If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, the payment provider stores your credit card information. It is encrypted by the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI) DSS. Your purchase transaction data will only be stored for as long as necessary to complete your purchase transaction.

All direct payment gateways comply with PCI-DSS standards, which are managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, a joint initiative of brands such as Visa, MasterCard, American Express, and Discover.

PCI DSS requirements help to ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

For more information, please read the Terms of Use and / or Payment Provider's Privacy Policy under the links below.

All personal data is collected only within the framework of a legal permit or if you have given us your consent.

### 2.2.4 Participation in sweepstakes / contests

Occasionally, competitions are offered on the website. We process and store your personal data, which you have specified when participating, for the performance of the respective sweepstakes / contests. In this case, the respective conditions of participation and privacy policy of the sweepstakes / contests apply, to which you will be separately referred in the context of the respective sweepstakes / contests. If you provide us with the necessary data, e.g. contact details for the prize notification, not provide, we cannot not perform the sweepstakes / contests properly.

## 2.3 Data that we process for the protection of legitimate interests of BITTERSTRAWBERRY, Art. 6 (1f) DS-GVO

### 2.3.1 Abuse prevention and recognition at conclusion of contract as well as address verification

At the conclusion of the contract, with the help of a visitor ID, which may contain anonymous control data of your used device (e.g. screen resolution, browser version or your operating system version) and with which your terminal is likely to be recognized on further visits, as well as with your specified contract data automatically checked for evidence of misuse of our offers. If there is suspicion of abuse, an employee reviews the rating and the underlying clues. If a contract is rejected, we will inform you. Objections to the rejection of a contract can be made at [fraud@bitterstrawberry.com](mailto:fraud@bitterstrawberry.com), whereupon the decision is again reviewed by an employee.

By processing the above mentioned personal data it´s aimed to be prevented on the one hand, that users specify wrong data or data from third parties upon conclusion of the contract (abuse prevention and recognition). On the other hand, it should be avoided that BITTERSTRAWBERRY incurs financial default risks in connection with the subscription agreement (credit check). The result of the credit check may possibly lead to restrictions on the method of payment or the rejection of a contract.

### 2.3.2 Direct Mailing

We want to offer the best deal to our customers and therefore use the address information we received from you in connection with the subscription contract to provide you with information about our BITTERSTRAWBERRY products (direct mail). You may object to the use of your data for the purpose of direct mail at any time at [privacy@bitterstrawberry.com](mailto:privacy@bitterstrawberry.com) without incurring other than the transmission costs according to the basic rates.

## 3\. To whom we transfer personal data

In this paragraph, we explain to whom we communicate personal information in connection with the use of our products and services at [www.bitterstrawberry.com](https://www.bitterstrawberry.com/) and, if we transfer data to a third country or an international organization, how we do that.

### 3.1 To whom we transmit data in connection with the processing of the subscription contract

Depending on the particular subscription, we will transfer personal data to the following recipients:

| Recipient | Purpose of transmission | Transfer to a third country or an international organization  
---|---|---|---  
| Third Party | For the purposes of contract execution, provided that they are concluded with the BITTERSTRAWBERRY subscription direct contractual relationships | MOBLAB SRL, Frunzei Street, no 26, 3rd floor, 021534 Bucharest, 2nd District, Romania  
| Cooperation and distribution partners | For billing purposes, provided your subscription has been obtained through such a partner | See section 2.2.3  
| BITTERSTRAWBERRY service provider | For the purposes of execution of the contract, provided that such service providers provide services on behalf of BITTERSTRAWBERRY necessary for the execution of the subscription relationship; Within the scope of this so-called processing on behalf of us (Art. 28 DS-GVO) we ensure the protection of your data through strict contractual arrangements, technical and organizational measures as well as additional controls | MOBLAB SRL, Frunzei Street, no 26, 3rd floor, 021534 Bucharest, 2nd District, Romania  
| Public Bodies | To fulfill priority legal obligations | A transfer of your personal data to third countries is currently not carried out and is not planned  
  
All other data regarding www.bitterstrawberry.com is stored on servers of

LeaseWeb Netherlands B.V.  
Luttenbergweg 8  
1101 EC Amsterdam  
T +31 20 316 2880  
F +31 20 316 2890  
Chamber of Commerce: 30141839  
VAT-number: NL812426939B01  
IBAN: NL27 DEUT 0543 8859 84  
BIC/SWIFT: DEUTNL2N  

Privacy Statement <https://www.leaseweb.com/sites/default/files/Legal/NL_ENG_Privacy_Statement.pdf>

### 3.2 To whom we transmit data when using webtracking tools

Detailed information on which providers we use when using webtracking tools such. To use cookies and which data is processed in this context, please refer to paragraph 5.

## 4\. How long we save your personal information

In the following we would like to inform you about how long we store personal data of you or, if the indication of a specific period is not possible, how the criteria for the determination of the retention period are.

We keep your information for the following periods; after expiration of these periods, the corresponding data will be routinely deleted.

| Type of Data | Retention Period  
---|---|---  
| Contract data (for example, purchase item, name, postal address, e-mail address, delivery address, payment method and bank details) | 10 years, starting from the end of the calendar year in which the contract was terminated / the service was last used  
  
Unless this data is affected, the data will be deleted if the purposes for which it was collected cease to exist or if you revoke a consent based on data processing.

In the event that a cancellation for legal, technical or organizational reasons is not possible or only with disproportionate effort, the processing of your data is restricted.

## 5\. What webtracking tools (cookies and other technologies) we use and how you can object to their use

When visiting our website, cookies can be set to make our website offerings more user-friendly for you. Cookies are small text files that are stored on the hard disk of your computer and that allow recognition, but do not allow personal identification of yourself. There are two types of cookies, so-called "session cookies", which remain on your device until you close the browser, and so-called "persistent cookies", which remain stored on your device for a certain period of time, even after you have closed the browser.

Web beacons (or so-called counting pixels) are also used with the same destination. Web beacons are small graphics that allow log file recording and log file analysis and are used for statistical analysis.

Below you will find an overview of the web tracking tools we use, as well as information on the purpose for which we use the web tracking tools and how to deactivate them if you do not want the necessary data processing ("opt-out"). For general information on how to prevent or manage the storage of cookies, please refer to para. 5.2.

### 5.1 Webtracking-tools we use

| Purpose | Tool / Provider | Description | Opt-Out  
---|---|---|---|---  
| Track the user behaivor, optimize the flow on the website  | Google LLC 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA | Google’s analytics improve engagement | [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy)  
| Record the user movments on the site and we can see the problem that he encounter so we can fix it | Hotjar Ltd, Level 2 St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street St Julians STJ 1000, Malta | track the user movments to make a heat map of the site | [https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out](https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy)  
  
## 5.2 How to object to the use of webtracking tools

### 5.2.1 Opposition to the display of personalized advertising

We offer you the possibility to prevent the display of personalized advertising by a single cookie. By clicking on the button below, a cookie is placed on your device that prevents the exploitation of usage-based online advertising on the BITTERSTRAWBERRY website as well as on websites of third parties, if this is based on the setting of third-party cookies on the BITTERSTRAWBERRY website. The cookie does not prevent the display of advertising in general, but prevents the exploitation of advertising tailored to your person. If you use several browsers, you must set this OptOut cookie in every browser.

**Usage-based online advertising**  
**[On / off button]**  

## 5.1 Webtracking-tools we use

### 5.2.2 Contradiction over browser settings

In addition to the individual possibilities of objection mentioned in section 4.1, you can generally prevent the storage of cookies by means of the settings of the browser you are using or you must agree that you must agree to the setting of cookies. You can also delete once set cookies at any time. If you use multiple browsers, you must make these settings in each of your browsers. Please note the instructions of your respective browser manufacturer. If you decline cookies altogether, this website may be impaired.

Please note that the contradiction of cookies is technically usually solved by setting a contradiction cookie. Thus, another cookie is stored on your device that prevents relevant information from being transmitted to the website operator. So if you delete the cookies stored on your device, you also delete these contradictory cookies. Later, a cookie - e.g. for website optimization - set, so again information is transmitted to the website operator.

### 5.3 Which social media plugins we use

We use so-called "social plugins" of various social networks on our website. When going to a BITTERSTRAWBERRY website that has such a plugin integrated, clicking the plugin will establish a connection between your browser and the social network servers. The information is then automatically transmitted to you about which BITTERSTRAWBERRY websites you have visited. If you are logged into the social network while visiting a BITTERSTRAWBERRY website with an integrated plugin, this information will be assigned to your social network account. If you are logged into a social network account with your browser and click on the plugin, the corresponding content will be shared on your social network account and linked to the account of the social network concerned. The purpose and scope of the data collection and the further processing and use of the data by the social networks, as well as your rights in this regard and setting options for the protection of your privacy, are based on the privacy policy of the respective social network:

If you do not agree with this transmission of data, please do not use the plugin functionality.

## 6\. Your Rights

Following, we would like to inform you about the rights that acc. Art. 15ff DS-GVO with regard to the processing of your personal data:

  * You have the right to request free information about your personal data stored by us.
  * You have the right to request the correction, deletion ("right to be forgotten") or restriction of the processing of your personal data.
  * You have the right to object to data processing that is necessary to safeguard the legitimate interests of BITTERSTRAWBERRY or a third party, or that is done for direct marketing purposes.
  * You have the right to receive the data concerning you in a structured, common and machine-readable format (the so-called "right to data portability").

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us as described in Section 1. If you believe that BITTERSTRAWBERRY´s processing of your personal information is contrary to applicable law, you may also contact the relevant regulatory authority.
